Oscar Castillejo

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/oscar-castillejo/ Email: oscar.castillejo.sa@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/oacs Mobile: +1-647-615-3226

Summary

Senior Software Developer (5+ years) with a strong background in Web and Mobile development using technologies such as Typescript, React.js (Redux), and AWS. I was a founding software engineer at Doorr, where I contributed to raising $\tilde{\$}1$ million in Series A seed funding and promptly addressed client-facing issues. Holds a Computer Science degree. Seeking a challenging role as a Backend developer.

EDUCATION

Universidad Católica Andrés Bello

Guayana, VE

Computer Science

Aug 2015 - Dec 2020

SKILLS SUMMARY

- Languages: Typescript, Javascript, PostgreSQL, MySQL, DynamoDB, GraphQL, Java, Go, SASS, CSS, Python
- Framework & Libraries: Express.js, Node.js, React.js (Redux), Vue.js (Vuex), TailwindCSS, Apollo, Rxjs, Nestjs
- Tools: AWS, Git, Docker, Jest, Cypress, Webpack, Jira, Confluence, Figma

EXPERIENCE

Finastra Mississauga, CA

Software Engineer Technical Lead

May 2022 - Feb 2023

- Technical desicion making: Led an international team of 10 developers to disrupt the Canadian mortgage industry taking care of code reviews, splitting efforts, design improvements and promoting quality code of 3 products
- Directing the Release Process: Directed the release process with live support of 7 major features for the Expert Proproduct and more than 20 hotfixes and small enhancements
- Core Feature Designer: Redesigned key workflows, resulting in a 25% increase in productivity (measured by decreased time to completion) and a streamlined, user-friendly experience. Worked with Product Owners to optimize workflows based on requirements.
- AWS Services Expertise: Frequently use various AWS services (RDS, DynamoDB, Api Gateway, SQS, Lamda, S3, CloudWatch)
- **Development Internship Program Director**: Designed and Directed our development internship program. This included: interviewing potential candidates; leading a team of interns to improve a web client, API, infrastructure and CI/CD; and work with project managers and stakeholders to ensure timely delivery
- Recognized for Outstanding Performance: Awarded 9 times within the organization for innovation, leading the team to success, outstanding performance and manage to solve critical situations on vacations

Doorr, acquired by Finastra

Mississauga, CA

 $Founding\ Software\ Engineer$

Aug 2020 - May 2022

- Library Compatibility Manager: Ensured dependencies and libraries were compatible and up to date with latest releases avoiding more than 120 vulnerabilities on the products
- Startup Contributor: One of three Back-end engineer at a startup that raised \$1 million in Series A seed funding design the foundations of core features such as CRM, Automations, External API, Websockets for real time updates and (i18n) solution on a full-stack perspective and always bringing ideas on how to improve all the process on the company
- Production Code Fixer: Promptly addressed client-facing issues reported by the Customer Success team delivering hotfixes to increase customers satisfaction on quick response times

Telesero United States
Frontend Developer Aug 2019 - Mar 2020

• Legacy Code Migration Specialist: Migrated legacy code to technologies such as React, Redux, improving the

- performance of the system with lower response time from 5 seconds to 1 second of load time

 Deskhoard and Maniter Web App Designer: Designed a Deskhoard and Maniter web app from scratch with
- Dashboard and Monitor Web App Designer: Designed a Dashboard and Monitor web app from scratch with real-time updates using Websocket and Rxjs, enhancing data representation through the implementation of interactive charts and graphs
- Material Design Implementation Specialist: Revamped the look and feel of the company's following the Material Design Patterns using Styled components, resulting in overall better UI/UX Improved user satisfaction by 90% with the implementation of intuitive navigation and better visual design elements

Pintosoft
Lead Web Developer

Venezuela

Jul 2018 - Mar 2019

• Crypto Gaming Web App Designer: Design web apps to motivate the usage of the company crypto currency with games and gambling features